Guide to the American Federation of Teachers, Local 1690 Records
Special Collections, University of Washington Libraries
American Federation of Teachers, Local 1690 records
1962-1976
University of Washington Libraries Special Collections Box 352900 Seattle, WA 98195-2900
5890
5890-001
American Federation of Teachers.$bLocal 1690 (Edmonds, Wash.)
2.64 cubic feet (3 boxes)
Organizational and affiliation records of the American Federation of Teachers, local 1690 labor union
American Federation of Teachers Local 1690, the Edmonds Federation of Teachers, was chartered about 1966. It competed with the NEA-affiliated Edmonds Education Association to represent K-12 teachers in the Edmonds, Washington School District #15. The local was most successful in gaining members from secondary schools. Local 1690 became inactive in 1986.
Organizational and affiliation records, meeting minutes, financial records, newsletters and publications, subject files, conferences and convention materials, strikes and negotiations, school district meeting records, ephemera, and membership records.
Forms Part of the Labor Archives of Washington
Open to all users.
Snohomish Central Labor Council Records (Mss Coll 3531)
Teachers' unions$zWashington (State)$zEdmonds$xHistory$vSources; Strikes and lockouts$zWashington (State)$zEdmonds$xHistory$vSources; Labor$zWashington (State)$zEdmonds; Labor unions$zWashington (State)$zEdmonds; Labor movement$zWashington (State)$zEdmonds; Constitutions; Minutes (Records); Business correspondence; Newsletters; Bumper stickers; Ephemera; Financial records; Labor Archives of Washington (University of Washington); American Federation of Teachers.$bLocal 1690 (Edmonds, Wash.)$vArchives; Personal Papers/Corporate Records; Labor Unions
- ORGANIZATIONAL AND AFFLIATION RECORDS, 1970-1976; SERIES I (Box-folder 1/1-13)
  - Constitution, 1972-1976 (Box-folder 1/1)
  - Elections, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 1/2)
  - Committees, 1973-1975 (Box-folder 1/3)
  - President duties, 1975 (Box-folder 1/4)
  - Membership, 1970-1974 (Box-folder 1/5)
  - Labor Council affiliation, Undated (Box-folder 1/6)
  - Constitutions of other organizations, 1970-1974 (Box-folder 1/7)
  - Washington State Federation of Teachers constitution, 1970-1975 (Box-folder 1/8)
  - Washington State Federation of Teachers elections, Undated (Box-folder 1/9)
  - Washington State Federation of Teachers membership, 1972-1974 (Box-folder 1/10)
  - Washington State Federation of Teachers Executive Board minutes, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 1/11)
  - Washington State Federation of Teachers directory, 1974 (Box-folder 1/12)
  - American Federation of Teachers directory (Box-folder 1/13)
- MINUTES, 1966-1972; SERIES II (Box-folder 1/14-16)
  - Minutes, 1966-1967 (Box-folder 1/14)
  - Minutes, 1968 (Box-folder 1/15)
  - Minutes, 1970-1972 (Box-folder 1/16)
- FINANCIAL RECORDS, 1967-1976; SERIES III (Box-folder 1/17-27)
  - EFT Treasurer, 1967-1977 (Box-folder 1/17)
  - Employer identification number, 1973 (Box-folder 1/18)
  - Insurance, 1972-1976 (Box-folder 1/19)
  - Budgets, 1971-1975 (Box-folder 1/20)
  - Income tax, 1967-1976 (Box-folder 1/21)
  - Office rental -- District building use, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 1/22)
  - Payroll deduction, 1971 (Box-folder 1/23)
  - EFT dues, 1974-1977 (Box-folder 1/24)
  - WSFT dues, 1972-1975 (Box-folder 1/25)
  - WSFT per capita payments, 1972-1976 (Box-folder 1/26)
  - AFT per capita payments, 1972-1976 (Box-folder 1/27)
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1966-1977; SERIES IV (Box-folder 1/28-47)
  - Incoming correspondence, 1966-1976 (Box-folder 1/28)
  - AFL-CIO, 1975 (Box-folder 1/29)
  - American Federation of Teachers, 1966-1977 (Box-folder 1/30)
  - Orders from AFT publications catalog, 1975 (Box-folder 1/31)
  - Edmonds Education Association, 1973-1977 (Box-folder 1/32)
  - Edmonds School District, 1971-1977 (Box-folder 1/33)
  - Superintendent, 1966-1975 (Box-folder 1/34)
  - Memo from Superintendent to employees, 1975 (Box-folder 1/35)
  - Everett strike, 1976 (Box-folder 1/36)
  - Extra duty policy, 1974 (Box-folder 1/37)
  - Industrial Welfare Committee, 1975 (Box-folder 1/38)
  - New York crisis, 1975 (Box-folder 1/39)
  - Payroll deduction of dues, 1970-1974 (Box-folder 1/40)
  - Renting Old Milltown Hall, 1976 (Box-folder 1/41)
  - Scholarship, 1971-1975 (Box-folder 1/42)
  - Surveys, 1967-1976 (Box-folder 1/43)
  - United Farm Workers, 1975 (Box-folder 1/44)
  - Washington Federation of Teachers, 1972-1976 (Box-folder 1/45)
  - Washington State Labor Council, 1972-1976 (Box-folder 1/46)
  - Workers' Education Local #189, 1976 (Box-folder 1/47)
- NEWSLETTERS AND PUBLICATIONS, 1966-1976; SERIES V (Box-folder 1/48-2/1)
  - Edmonds Federation of Teachers publications, 1966-1971 (Box-folder 1/48)
  - Edmonds Federation of Teachers publications, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 1/49)
  - Edmonds Federation of Teachers publications, 1972-1973 (Box-folder 1/50)
  - EForT newsletter, 1974-1975 (Box-folder 1/51)
  - Edmonds Education Association publications, 1966-1970 (Box-folder 1/52)
  - Edmonds Education Association publications, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 1/53)
  - Edmonds Education Association Viewpoint newsletter, 1972-1973 (Box-folder 1/54)
  - Edmonds Education Association Viewpoint newsletter, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 1/55)
  - Edmonds Education Association Viewpoint newsletter, 1974-1975 (Box-folder 1/56)
  - Edmonds Education Association Viewpoint newsletter, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 1/57)
  - Everett Teacher, 1976 (Box-folder 1/58)
  - Other AFT local publications, 1966-1975 (Box-folder 1/59)
  - Union Teacher, Washington Teacher, 1974-1975 (Box-folder 1/60)
  - Washington Association of School Administrators Hotline, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 1/61)
  - AFT in Action, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 1/62)
  - Edmonds School District Staff Notes, 1975 (Box-folder 1/63)
  - Memo from COPE, 1975-1977 (Box-folder 1/64)
  - Washington State Labor Council, 1974-1976 (Box-folder 1/65)
  - Ideas for publication, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 1/66)
  - American Federation of Teachers Publications, 1966-1970 (Box-folder 2/1)
- SUBJECT FILES, 1962-1977; SERIES VI (Box-folder 2/2-52)
  - Academic freedom literature, 1972 (Box-folder 2/2)
  - Accountability, 1972 (Box-folder 2/3)
  - Agency shop, 1970-1972 (Box-folder 2/4)
  - AFT publications catalog, 1971-1973 (Box-folder 2/5)
  - AFT services, 1974-1977 (Box-folder 2/6)
  - Arbitration, 1972-1974 (Box-folder 2/7)
  - Attorney General's Office, 1973 (Box-folder 2/8)
  - Attorneys, 1972-1976 (Box-folder 2/9)
  - Boycott, 1975 (Box-folder 2/10)
  - Classroom observation and learning atmosphere, 1974-1975 (Box-folder 2/11)
  - Coalition for Protective Legislation, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 2/12)
  - Committee on Political Education (C.O.P.E.), Initiative 314, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 2/13)
  - Desegragation and equality in education, 1976 (Box-folder 2/14)
  - District #15 insurance, 1976 (Box-folder 2/15)
  - Early childhood education, 1976 (Box-folder 2/16)
  - EFT building stewards, 1974 (Box-folder 2/17)
  - Edmonds salaries, 1972-1974 (Box-folder 2/18)
  - Financial aid: WSFT, 1973 (Box-folder 2/19)
  - Grievance procedure, 1968-1973 (Box-folder 2/20)
  - Levies, 1976 (Box-folder 2/21)
  - Membership drive, 1976 (Box-folder 2/22)
  - Merger guidelines, 1973-1975 (Box-folder 2/23)
  - Merger breakup, 1974 (Box-folder 2/24)
  - Merit pay, 1962-1972 (Box-folder 2/25)
  - Nixon, 1973 (Box-folder 2/26)
  - PEMCO insurance, 1966-1972 (Box-folder 2/27)
  - Performance contracting, 1972 (Box-folder 2/28)
  - Portland election, 1971 (Box-folder 2/29)
  - Prescription discounts, 1972 (Box-folder 2/30)
  - Probation - Noe case, 1974 (Box-folder 2/31)
  - Retroactive pay, 1972 (Box-folder 2/32)
  - Seattle Community College Federation of Teachers strike, 1972 (Box-folder 2/33)
  - Seven-period day, 1974 (Box-folder 2/34)
  - Snohomish County Labor Council, 1975 (Box-folder 2/35)
  - Statewide salary schedule, 1974 (Box-folder 2/36)
  - Student teacher membership, Undated (Box-folder 2/37)
  - Superintendent of Public Instruction, 1973 (Box-folder 2/38)
  - Tacoma Federation of Teachers, 1976 (Box-folder 2/39)
  - Teacher benefits from unions, 1975 (Box-folder 2/40)
  - Teacher certification, 1966-1968 (Box-folder 2/41)
  - Teacher evaluation, 1965-1986 (Box-folder 2/42)
  - Teacher militancy, 1973 (Box-folder 2/43)
  - Teacher pensions, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 2/44)
  - Teacher rights: Washington State, 1967 (Box-folder 2/45)
  - Teacher strikes, 1970-1975 (Box-folder 2/46)
  - Teacher tenure, 1970-1972 (Box-folder 2/47)
  - Unemployment compensation for teachers, 1975 (Box-folder 2/48)
  - Union films, 1969-1976 (Box-folder 2/49)
  - United Teacher Press Association, 1976 (Box-folder 2/50)
  - Vouchers, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 2/51)
  - Washington Association of School Administrators, 1976 (Box-folder 2/52)
- CONFERENCES AND CONVENTIONS, 1975-1976; SERIES VII (Box-folder 2/53-54)
  - A.F.T. Convention, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 2/53)
  - Pacific Northwest Labor History Conference, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 2/54)
- STRIKES AND NEGOTIATIONS, 1963-1976; SERIES VIII (Box-folder 2/55-68)
  - Negotiations, 1974-1975 (Box-folder 2/55)
  - Edmonds Strike (Part 1 of 2) (H.F.T.), 1973 (Box-folder 2/56)
  - Edmonds Strike (Part 2 of 2), 1972-1974 (Box-folder 2/57)
  - E.E.A. Package, 1974-1975 (Box-folder 2/58)
  - Contract, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 2/59)
  - Collective Bargaining Agreements (Samples), 1970-1975 (Box-folder 2/60)
  - Picket Duty, Undated (Box-folder 2/61)
  - Negotiations Law, 1963-1973 (Box-folder 2/62)
  - Larry Burke, 1968-1975 (Box-folder 2/63)
  - Contracts, 1972-1973 (Box-folder 2/64)
  - R.I.F. and Program Restoration (Part 1 of 2), 1975-1976 (Box-folder 2/65)
  - R.I.F. and Program Restoration (Part 2 of 2), 1975-1976 (Box-folder 2/66)
  - AFT Negotiations Manual (Part 1 of 2), c. 1974 (Box-folder 2/67)
  - AFT Negotiations Manual (Part 2 of 2), c. 1974 (Box-folder 2/68)
- SCHOOL DISTRICT MEETING RECORDS, 1973-1976; SERIES IX (Box-folder 3/1-7)
  - Minutes and reports, 1973 (Box-folder 3/1)
  - Minutes and reports (Part 1 of 2), 1974 (Box-folder 3/2)
  - Minutes and reports (Part 2 of 2), 1974 (Box-folder 3/3)
  - Minutes and reports (Part 1 of 2), 1975 (Box-folder 3/4)
  - Minutes and reports (Part 2 of 2), 1975 (Box-folder 3/5)
  - Minutes and reports (Part 1 of 2), 1976 (Box-folder 3/6)
  - Minutes and reports (Part 2 of 2), 1976 (Box-folder 3/7)
- EPHEMERA, 1972-1976; SERIES X (Box-folder 3/8-12)
  - Bumper stickers, Undated (Box-folder 3/8)
  - Cartoons, 1972-1973 (Box-folder 3/9)
  - Map of District #15, c. 1972 (Box-folder 3/10)
  - News clippings, 1973-1976 (Box-folder 3/11)
  - Songs, Undated (Box-folder 3/12)
- MEMBERSHIP RECORDS, 1970-1975; SERIES XI (Box-folder 3/13-3/15)
  - Membership applications, 1971 (Box-folder 3/13)
  - Membership applications, 1973 (Box-folder 3/14)
  - Membership lists, 1970-1975 (Box-folder 3/15)